shop.com 2018-06-24

# SHOP.COM - Online Shopping Marketplace: Clothes, Shoes, Beauty, Electronics and More

You are using an **outdated** browser. Please [upgrade your browser](http://browsehappy.com/) to improve your experience.

SHOP MA, Inc. and its family of sites, www.shop.com, uk.shop.com, ca.shop.com, au.shop.com, www.shop-com.jp, mx.shop.com, theshoppingvine.com, www.shopcompanion.com, www.cataloguecity.co.uk, dwellvine.com, gadgettevine.com, glammevine.com and solevine.com (individually and collectively the "Site") is dedicated to protecting the privacy of our valued online customers (and has been since 1997). We created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate its firm commitment to the safety of your personal information.

Our mission is to provide the most compelling shopping experience for our customers. We want you to feel safe while visiting the Site.

Third party Information. We may permit web analytics and other providers to collect and process information on our websites using the technologies described above. Some of these providers have information about you, including personal information, demographic information and interest reports. They may share this information with us and we may share your personal information with them. Third Party Information helps us to enhance and personalize our interactions with you so that the information you receive is more relevant to you. We use third party information for behavioral advertising, which allows us to predict your preferences and to show you ads and send you e-mails that are more likely to interest you.

This Privacy Policy outlines some of the types of personal information we receive and collect, and how we use that information. We hope this Privacy Policy will help you make an informed decision about sharing your personal information with us.

This Privacy Policy covers the following information:

  1. The types of personally identifiable information collected about you during your relationship with SHOP MA, Inc.
  2. How we use and share the information that we collect from you.
  3. The choices you have about the collection, use and sharing of your personally identifiable information.
  4. The types of security procedures we take to safeguard your personally identifiable information.
  5. How you may access, update and change personally identifiable information you've provided.
  6. California Residents.
  7. Other Information.
  8. How you can ask questions, or send us comments about this Privacy Policy.

Your use of the Site constitutes your acceptance of this Privacy Policy and your consent to the practices it describes. The information we learn from customers helps us personalize and continually improve the shopping experience at the Site.

### Types of Personally Identifiable Information We Collect

While you visit the Site we collect various types of personally identifiable information (PII). Here are the types of information we gather:

  1. Information You Provide Us.  
Much of the personally identifiable information we receive comes directly from customers who are interested in obtaining various products and services by shopping at the Site. Typically, this information includes your name, postal address, email address and telephone number. We may also collect other types of information such as gender, age, number of children, and personal interests, which we may associate with personally identifiable information. If you purchase products or services through the Site we will note, for example, credit card information, the type of services or products ordered or purchased, and the date of the order or purchase. We collect personal information when you register, log on, or visit the Site, including when you participate in activities on the Site, such as by placing an order, completing a user registration form or online survey, creating an address book, using our Shopping or Gift Services (including eGifts, Gift Certificates, Gift Registry, Bridal Registry, Reminder Service), or participating in a rebate offer, game, promotion, contest or sweepstakes.
  2. Information From Others.  
We are constantly improving the products and services we provide our customers. To aid in serving you better we may supplement personally identifiable information that we have collected directly from our customers with other information that we obtain from third parties or from our partner stores. In addition, we may obtain information about individuals who are not yet users of the Site. To ensure your privacy when we associate information that we obtain from third parties with personally identifiable information that we have collected under this Privacy Policy, we will treat the acquired information like the information that we collected ourselves.
  3. Information Collected Through Technology.  
We collect information through technology to make the Site more interesting and useful to you. For instance, when you come to the Site, we collect your IP address. An IP address is often associated with the portal through which you enter the Internet, like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. Standing alone, your IP address is not personally identifiable. At times, we also use IP addresses to collect information regarding the frequency with which our customers visit various parts of the Site. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information as more fully described in paragraph 1a. above.

We also use cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a site sends to your computer while you are viewing the site. Cookies are used for a variety of purposes. For instance, when you return to the Site after logging in, cookies provide information to the Site so that the Site will remember you. We may also use temporary or "session" cookies to help you shop. These cookies will expire when you place an order. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your experience on the Site smoother, like the features mentioned above, and some of our services will not function properly including the shopping cart and checkout areas. Some of our business partners may also use cookies on the Site; however, we have no access to, or control over, these cookies and do not accept any responsibility for such use.

The Site use a variety of technical methods for tracking purposes, including web beacons. Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of web sites. We may use these technical methods to analyze the traffic patterns on the Site, such as the frequency with which our users visit various parts of the Site. These technical methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to another party authorized by us to collect information on our behalf. We also use these technical methods in HTML emails that we send our customers to determine whether customers have opened those emails and/or clicked on links in those emails. The information from use of these technical methods may be collected in a form that is personally identifiable.

The Site includes third party advertising and links to other web sites such as Google, advertising.com or shopping.com. These companies are called "network advertisers." We do not provide any personally identifiable information to these network advertisers. Network advertisers who place advertisements on the Site, or third parties with whom we have a relationship, may also use cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information. You may not realize this information is being collected. In some cases, we may have access to information from web beacons and cookies used by network advertisers on the Site and this information may permit us to identify other sites that you have visited that are also associated with the network advertiser. Once you have clicked on an advertisement and have left the Site, our Privacy Policy no longer applies and you must read the privacy policy of the advertiser to see how your personal information will be handled on their site. You should contact these advertisers directly if you have any questions about their use of the information that they collect.

### How We Use and Share the Personally Identifiable Information We Collect

  1. Use by SHOP MA, Inc.  
We may use personally identifiable information for Operational Uses such as helping to establish and verify the identity of users; opening, maintaining, administering and servicing user accounts; processing, servicing or enforcing transactions and sending related service communications; providing services and support to users such as eGifts, Gift Certificates, Gift Registry, Bridal Registry, Reminders, rebates, contests, sweepstakes, and address books; improving the Site (including tailoring it to users' preferences); providing users with service or product updates, promotional notices and offers; responding to your questions, inquiries, comments and instructions; and maintaining the security and integrity of our systems. We may also use personally identifiable information to provide offers, promotions and product updates to you via standard mail. Your email address and other personally identifiable information may be used by us or any subsidiary, parent, affiliate or other corporation into which we merge or is otherwise acquired or sold, in whole or in part ("affiliates"). We welcome you to post reviews, comments, articles, stories and other appropriate content; send ecards and other communications; and submit suggestions, ideas, comments, questions, or other information. You can also share your shopping ideas, ratings, reviews, purchases and other information through Facebook and other third party sharing features. Information or content submitted may be used by us or our affiliates to provide other consumers with product reviews and shopping information. If you do post content or submit material, and unless we indicate otherwise, you grant us a nonexclusive, fee-free, royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable, and fully sublicensable right to use, reproduce, modify, adapt, publish, translate, create derivative works from, distribute, and display such content throughout the world in any media. You also grant us the right to use the name or home town that you submit in connection with such content. Your personally identifiable information may be used by us or any subsidiary, parent or other corporation into which we merge or are otherwise acquired or sold, in whole or in part ("affiliates").
  2. Use of Your Email Address Or Email Address You Provide to Us.  
Your email is considered personally identifiable information. In addition to other ways we are permitted to use personally identifiable information, we may also use your email address for processing, servicing or enforcing transactions and sending related service communications; providing users with service or product updates, promotional notices and offers; and/or responding to your questions, inquiries or comments. Your email address may be used by us or any subsidiary, parent or other corporation into which we merge or is otherwise acquired or sold, in whole or in part. If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our Site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Site. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact [Customer Service](mailto:customerservice@shop.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.
  3. Use by Merchant Partners.  
We share information about you with our Merchant Partners for Fulfillment Uses such as using your email address for shipping and other contact information for purposes of processing, servicing or enforcing transactions and sending order status and other related communications. If you order products from Alice.com they will receive your order information, name, address, telephone number, age and gender, as well as any other information necessary to properly fullfill your order. Their treatment of your Personal Information will be governed by the terms of their Privacy Statement, which we will always provide for your review during checkout, when an Alice.com product is in your cart. You can contact each Merchant Partner by clicking on the "Stores" tab, then locating the particular Merchant Partner and finding contact information in the "Store Info" link.
  4. Co-Branding Partners.  
We have Co-Branding Partners that provide unique benefits to certain loyal customers. In Co-Branded Partnerships, we may acquire, share with our Co-Branding Partners or use personally identifiable information identified in paragraph 1.a., above, to communicate special offers, provide additional benefits or for other related uses.
  5. Independent Shop Consultants.  
In order to provide the best service to our customers, we will assign you an independent Shop Consultant. We share your order information, some of your personally identifiable information and information about your spending habits with the person or business entity assigned as your Shop Consultant. Your opt-out choices under paragraph 3 below will not apply to our sharing of your personal information with independent Shop Consultants.
  6. Charitable Organizations.  
We may offer opportunities for you to make purchases or donations to promote the charitable mission of certain organizations. When you participate in these offers, your personally identifiable information may be forwarded to the charitable organization so that it may recognize your donation and provide follow up communication.
  7. Affiliate, Parent and Subsidiary Companies.  
In order to provide the best service to our customers, we may share your personally identifiable information and information about your spending habits with our Affiliate, Parent and Subsidiary companies, including without limitation, Market America Worldwide, Inc., Market America, Inc., Shop.com Market Place, Inc. and Market Australia, Inc.
  8. Companies that Facilitate Communications and Transactions with You.  
Sometimes we hire companies to help deliver messages or services, such as a company that helps fulfill prizes for a sweepstakes or assists us in the analysis of consumer data, development of new services, sending email, credit card processing, sending catalogs or other promotional mailings; or providing customer assistance or marketing assistance. In those instances, there is a need to share your information with these companies. Sometimes we also work with other companies who help either gather your information or communicate with you. Your opt-out choices under paragraph 3 below will not apply to our sharing of your personal information with any of these companies. These third parties are required to maintain your information in strictest confidence and to ensure they honor the privacy settings you have selected for the handling of your private information. Nonetheless, except as separately permitted by other provisions of this Privacy Policy, these companies are allowed to gather, receive, and use your information only for the purposes described in this paragraph or as required by law. The personal identifiable information that may be shared is more fully described in paragraph 1a. above.
  9. Disclosures Required By Law and Disclosures to Help Protect the Security and Safety of Our Sites, and Others.  
Regardless of any opt-out choices that you make under paragraph 3, we will disclose personal information when we believe in good faith that such disclosures (a) are required by law, including, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena, or (b) will help to: enforce our Terms of Use; enforce contest, sweepstakes, promotions, and/or game rules; protect your safety or security, including the safety and security of property that belongs to you; and/or, protect the safety and security of our Site, SHOP MA, Inc., and/or third parties, including the safety and security of property that belongs to SHOP MA Inc. or third parties.
  10. Third-Party Marketers.  
We do not rent or sell your personal information with third-party marketers without first obtaining your consent. Should this policy change in the future, we will post a notification of those changes to the Site.
  11. Card Linked Offers.   
For information on how we may use the payment card information and transaction details that you provide or we receive from third parties in connection with card-linked offers, please see the SHOP Local [Card Linking Terms of Use](https://img.shop.com/Image/resources/shoplocal/ShopLocal_Card_Linking_TermsofUse.pdf).

### Your choices about the collection, use and sharing of your personally identifiable information

You may choose to opt-out (or decline to give us), your consent to use personally identifiable information for the purposes of receiving promotional materials from us, from our Merchant Partners, our Co-Branding Partners and/or our Affiliate, Parent and Subsidiary Companies. There are several methods by which you can exercise your opt-out choices: (a) during the registration process on our Site; (b) after registration, by logging on our Site, clicking on our My Account link, Privacy Policy links or going to My Account - Edit My Privacy Settings and following the opt-out directions; (c) by emailing or writing SHOP MA, Inc. using the contact information provided below; (d) promotional emails you receive from us will provide you with an "unsubscribe" option; and (e) at other times and locations on the Site. Each of these opt-out choices is subject to the exceptions described further below.

Please keep in mind that any opt-out choices you make will not apply in situations where (a) you either have made, simultaneously make, or later make a specific request for information from us, (b) we use your personal information for either "Operational Uses" or "Fulfillment Uses" (as described above in paragraph 2), (c) we share your personal information under the provisions of paragraph 2 above with respect to "Companies That Facilitate Communications and Transactions With You," "Independent Shop Consultants" or "Disclosures Required By Law and Disclosures to Help Protect the Security and Safety of Our Sites and Others."

Finally, if you do not exercise your opt-out choices upon registration or initial log-in at our Site, it may take up to ten (10) days for your opt-out choices to become effective. As our systems require time to update, promotional mailings using personal information shared before you opt-out may already be in process. Thus, you might continue to receive promotional materials from us based upon the personal information you have provided under this Privacy Policy for up to ten (10) days. For similar reasons, your personal information might continue to be shared with third parties for promotional purposes for up to ten (10) days.

### Security Measures to protect your personal information

The security and confidentiality of your information is extremely important to us. We have implemented technical, administrative, and physical security measures to protect your information from unauthorized access and improper use. On a regular basis, we review our security procedures in order to consider appropriate new technology and methods. Please be aware, however, that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your email address, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Whether you're ordering a catalog or making a purchase, we want you to feel safe and secure while visiting the Site. You can also feel confident making purchases from established Co-Branded Partner sites. To ensure that your credit card information is even more secure, we use secure sockets layer (SSL) software (which encrypts the information you input) when you give us your credit card information. We encrypt all credit card information and store it on a server that isn't accessible on the Internet. Once we store that information, it can not be displayed anywhere on the Site. Internally, we take extra caution to limit access to customers' information. Only a few individuals within the company are given degrees of access to customers' personal information according to job function and necessity. Access is granted to these employees through special passwords. All employees are kept up to date on our security and privacy practices. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. If you have any questions about security on the Site, you can send an email to us at [customerservice@shop.com](mailto:customerservice@shop.com).

### How can you access, update your information and opt out choices

You can access and update the contact information you gave us during registration (that is, your postal address, email address, or any other information that would directly enable us to contact you), or modify your opt-out choices, by going to My Account. You also have the ability to add new credit card or shipping information to My Account when placing an order. If you have elected to store your credit card information with us, we only display the last four digits of your credit card number in the saved payment methods in the My Account section. The full credit card information is stored on secure offline servers. For more information on how we protect your credit card information, see our Security section.

If you want to review, modify or correct any of this information, simply click on this link or go to the My Account center on the Site, and then log in with your member name and password. If you have forgotten your password, there are instructions on the link above to help you recover your password. If you need to recover your password, you can also contact us via email at customerservice@shop.com. Please include information in the email that will help us identify your account so we can assist you with your request. We may also provide you an opportunity to update your contact information and/or modify your opt-out choices by sending you an email or other communication that invites your response. Finally, you may unsubscribe from certain email communications by clicking on unsubscribe links in those emails.

### CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the Shine The Light law, permits SHOP.COM customers who are California residents to request information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident you may submit your request for this information to: [customerservice@shop.com](mailto:%20customerservice@shop.com)

Regular mail:  
SHOP MA, Inc   
3301 NE 1st Ave.  
Miami, FL 33137   
email: [customerservice@shop.com](mailto:%20customerservice@shop.com)

### Other Information

  1. Child Use.  
We do not knowingly collect personal information from, or sell products for purchase by, persons under the age of 18. We sell children's products for purchase by adults. Do not provide information to us, or purchase from this Site, if you are under the age of 18.
  2. Legal Disclaimer.  
We may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on our Site.
  3. Notification of Changes.  
Our business changes constantly and our Privacy Policy will change accordingly. You should check our Site frequently to view recent changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.

If we decide to change our email practices, we will post those changes to the Site so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

### Questions, Comments, Contact Information Regarding our Privacy Policy

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:  
SHOP MA, Inc   
3301 NE 1st Ave.  
Miami, FL 33137   
email: [customerservice@shop.com](mailto:%20customerservice@shop.com)

Updated September 21, 2017
